http://www.coolchile.co.uk/privacy-and-cookies

Free Delivery on orders over £50
UK Mainland Only (excluding alcohol)
Click & Collect Your Order
From Cool Chile HQ (W3)
Privacy and Cookies
Below you can find our privacy policy, and information on the cookies used by the Cool Chile website.Updated: 22/05/2018This Privacy policy applies to the Cool Chile website and governs data collection and usage. By using www.coolchile.co.uk website, you consent to the data practices outlined below.OUR COMMITMENT TO DATA SECURITYWe have put in place several physical, electronic, and managerial safeguarding procedures to secure the information we collect online.HOW AND WHY DO WE USE YOUR PERSONAL DATAWhen you make a purchase through our website, we collect some personally identifiable information, such as your e-mail address, title, first and last name, company name (optional), billing address, delivery address, telephone numbers, date of your first order or the date your account was set up. We use this information to:* to provide goods to you and enable our customer service to interact with you regarding orders and deliveries* to verify your identity* with your agreement, to contact you electronically about recipes, promotional offers, new products and Cool Chile updates* where we have a legal right or duty to use or disclose your information (for example in relation to an investigation by a public authority or in a legal dispute)* for crime and fraud prevention, detection and related purposesFurther to this specific customer information, the database will also hold records of a customer's shopping baskets and their orders (both successful and unsuccessful).We do utilise the services of third-party provider software to provide services to you and that can involve the sharing of some of your information which may be hosted on third-party servers. A list of third-party services that we use are:Google Analytics: to monitor website performance and users usage of itWorldpay – system for taking card payments online and over the telephoneWebsite hosting: BytemarkCampaign Monitor: Email campaigns and newslettersDPD and Royal Mail: DeliveryCool Chile do not sell, lease or share its customer lists to third parties other than those specified above.We have vetted the security of these services as being of good quality. We encourage you to read the privacy statements of these companies on their websites. HOW DO WE PROTECT YOUR DATACool Chile is committed to keeping your personal data safe and secure, our customer database is hosted in a secure hosting environment. The database credentials are stored in a secure and encrypted environment.REQUIRED INFORMATIONTo place an order with Cool Chile, you must provide your name, billing address, phone number and email address, the billing address is required for online payments to be processed. Your phone number and email address are required to be able to make contact in the event of any changes to your order or delivery.WHAT ARE YOUR RIGHTS?Cool Chile does not use or disclose any personal information without your explicit consent. You may, at any time, request to see the information we are holding of yours and you have the right to have the data deleted on request. To contact us regarding your personal data please use our online form or call the office on 0208 969 5640. If you call, we will need to identify you and may need to ask for an email address or other personal identifier.KEEPING IN TOUCHFor our ‘customers', we use your personal data for certain legitimate business purposes, for example we may ask for your name and email, to tell you about new products and services and to send you marketing communication and offers on our website.We want to keep you up to date with information about new ranges, special offers and improvements to our website. When you set your account up, we will ask you if you want to receive this type of marketing information.Cool Chile will not share your details with anyone outside of Cool Chile Co.If you decide you no longer want to receive emails from us, you can unsubscribe using the option at the bottom of each email communication we send to you or you can also contact us by email: info@coolchile.co.uk, telephone: 0208 969 5640 or in writing to: 46 Westwood Trading Park, Acton, W3 0TH.We will not hold your details for longer than legally required. DO YOU KEEP MY CREDIT/DEBIT CARD DETAILS ON FILE?We do not keep any records of your credit/debit card details within our organisation in any form, either written, electronically or in a database. Once you enter your card details online, the transaction is processed via our payment processer and no payment details are recorded by us.When you place an order with us over the telephone, your credit/debit card details are processed and entered directly into our world pay system and there is no record of your financial details retained by our organisation.HOW LONG DO WE KEEP YOUR INFORMATION?We hold your details on file for as long as legally required.WHAT YOU CAN DO TO HELP PROTECT YOUR DATACool Chile will never ask you to send your bank details or credit card detail via an email. If you receive an email claiming to be from Cool Chile and requesting any of your personal data, please do not respond.If you are logged into your Cool Chile account in a public place, please ensure you log out and keep your passwords private.COOKIES1. First party cookies (Cookies that Cool Chile set)“session” - This cookie is used by Cool Chile’s website to store information about the user’s current session, such as whether they are logged in, as well as user preferences when using the website.2. Third party cookies (Cookies set by third party scripts)“_ga, _gid, _gat, _utm*” - These cookies are set by Google’s analytics product, “Google Analytics”. Cool Chile uses Google Analytics to measure the website's usage and ensure we’re providing the best possible service to our users. The information collected by Google Analytics is anonymous.
